조이, 안녕!
Oh, hey, Joey.
Mmm. Hey.
안녕
Listen, um, I need to ask you something.
나 부탁이 하나 있어
Okay, you know how my stepdad's in prison?
내 양아버지 감옥에 계신 거 알지?
yeah, well, um, listen, he was supposed to get a weekend furlough so he could come to the wedding tomorrow,
원래는 주말에 나오셔서
내일 결혼식에 오시기로 했었거든
그런데 방금 통화를 했는데...
but he just called and, well, apparently, stabbing "iceman"in the exercise yard just couldn't wait until Monday, so...
운동장에 있던 사람을
칼로 찌르는 바람에
하루만 더 참으면 큰일나나
- 그래서 못오신다는 거야?
- 그래
so, he can't come?
No.
결혼식에 날 데리고 들어갈
사람이 없어져버렸어
And so there's no one to walk me down the aisle,
그래서 말인데...
and, well, I would just really love it if you would do it.
네가 해준다면 정말 좋을것 같아
정말이야?
Seriously?
그럼~ 넌 아빠같은 존재였다구
Yeah. You've, you know, sort of been like a dad to me.
I mean, you've always, you know, looked out for me and shared your wisdom.
항상 날 돌봐줬고
많은 지식을 나눠줬어
하긴 내가 좀 '지식적'이긴 하지
I am pretty wisdomis.
그럼... 해줄 수 있어?
So, what do you say?
Are you kidding? Phoebe, I would be honored.
지금 농담해?
오히려 내가 영광이지
Oh... thank you.
정말 고마워
Ooh...
정말...
I hope... I hope you know how much you mean to me.
네가 나한테 얼마나 소중한지
알아줬으면 좋겠어
Listen. I hope... I hope that you know...
난 네가...
아빠가 우는 걸 보여주긴 싫다
I don't want you to see your father cry. Go to your room!
저리 가렴!
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
10x12 The One With Phoebe's Wedding
[제 작]
코리아닷컴 프렌즈동호회 자막팀
[해 석]
윤미내(minaii@korea.com)
[자막] 최성일(csi4387@msn.com)
[테스터]
김종옥(joscool76@korea.com)
[싱 커]
임욱재(sys_friends6@korea.com)
임의 수정 및 상업적용도의 사용을 금합니다
(club.korea.com/friends)
수정사항은 피드백 게시판에 남겨주세요
Oh, here.
Oh, no, no, no. Let your dad get this. Ah..
아니다, 얘야
아빠가 사줄게
oh... it's my wedding planner. She's driving me crazy.
웨딩플래너 때문에
정말 미쳐버릴 것 같아
여보세요
Hello.
Hey, okay, stop screaming.
알았어, 소리지르지 마!
가자미로 해
Okay, so halibut. All right, so salmon, either way, I don't... it doesn't matter to me!
그럼 연어로 하든가
아무거나... 난 상관없다구!
내가 상관있다니깐!
Well, it matters to me!
Well... I don't care, so you pick.
난 상관없으니까 네가 골라
너 지금 내 전화를 끊어버린 거야?
Did you just hang up on me?
All right, look.I need you at the rehearsal dinner tonight at 18:00 hours.
오늘 18시00분에
저녁식사 리허설이 있어
좋아, 그게 몇신데?
Uh-huh. Okay. What time is that?
군대용어도 몰라?
You don't know military time?
아마 미사일훈련 받느라고
그날 못들었나 봐
I must have been in missile training the day they taught that.
12를 빼면 되잖아
Just subtract 12.
알았어, 1800에서
12를 빼면 1788이니까...
Okay, so, 1,800 minus 12 is 1,788...
- 6시야!
- 알았어
Six o'clock!
Okay.
잠깐만...
겔러입니다
Hold on. Yeah.
Geller here.
No, I said it has to be there by 4:00. Good-bye.
안돼요!
4시까지 와야 한댔잖아요!
안녕히 계세요!
얼음조각 하나놓는 게
이렇게 힘들 줄이야
God, how hard is it to make an ice sculpture?
Ice sculpture? That sounds really fancy.I told you, I just want a simple wedding.
얼음조각? 그건 너무 화려하잖아
난 그냥 검소하게 하고 싶댔잖아
Please. Honey,leave the details to me.
제발, 피비
자잘한 것들은 나한테 맡겨
내가 할 수 있는 한
특별한 날이 되게 하고 싶어서 그래
Now, I want to make this day as special for you as I can.
하프 연주자는
흰색을 입는게 좋겠고...
Now, okay, I was thinking that the harpist should wear white.
뭐라구? 하프?
내 친구 마조리는 드럼치는데?
Well, harpist?
My friend Marjorie is playing the steel drums.
아~ 그 친구가 밀렸어
Oh, she backed out.
진짜? 왜?
She did? Why?
내가 시켰어
I made her.
우아한 결혼식에
드럼은 너무 안어울려
Steel drums don't really say elegant wedding,
nor does marjorie's overwhelming scent.
그리고 그 친구 너무 냄새 나
야!
Hey. She will shower when tibet is free.
그 애도 티벳이 독립하면 씻을거야!
안녕~ 너 너무 예쁘다!
Hey. You look great.
Hey. You, too.
I'm so glad we're having this rehearsal dinner.You know, I so rarely get to practice my meals before I eat them.
리허설 하게 돼서 너무 다행이야
밥 먹기 전에 미리
연습할 수 있어서 말이지
우리가 무슨 선물 하나만
해주면 된댔지?
Okay, what did we say was your one gift to us?
바보같은 농담 하지 말기
No stupid jokes.
내일 결혼식 때 하지는
마라는 것인줄 알았지
But I thought that was for the actual wedding.
Rehearse it.
그것도 리허설 해
안녕~
Hi.
와줘서 고마워
Thanks for coming, you guys.
Oh, yeah. Oh.
나... 난 악수하려고 했던 건데
I, uh, I was, uh, I was going for a handshake.
그래서 지금 거길 누르고 있는거군
Is that why your hand is pressed against my crotch?
바로 그렇지
That is why.
Yeah.
레이첼, 에마는?
Rach?
Yeah?
Where's Emma?
Oh, Monica made me send her to my mother's.Apparently, babies and weddings don't mix.
모니카가 엄마한테 맡기랬어
결혼이랑 아기는 당연히 안맞잖아
너 그놈의 애기 때문에 투덜대니?
Are you still crying about your damn baby?
Phoebes... you got to keep the line moving. Remember, 20 seconds per person.
피비, 손님 줄 잘 빠지게 하랬잖아
한명당 20초라니깐
얘네들은 맨날 보잖아
You see these clowns all the time.
안녕하세요
마이크의 부모님이시죠?
Hey, you're Mike's parents, right?
네, 그래요
Yes, we are.
Oh... our little ones are growing up fast, aren't they?
애들이 참 빨리 크죠?
어떻다구요?
How's that?
한편으로는 기쁘지만
한편으로는 섭섭하잖아요
You know, on the one hand, you're happy for them, but on the other hand, it's hard to let go.
도대체 당신 누구요?!
Who in god's name are you?
이것 봐요, 나도 당신 둘 다
별로 맘에 안들어요
Hey, I'm not that fond of you either, okay, buddy, but I'm just trying to be nice for the kids.
애들 때문에 잘 지내보려고 그런거지
You know what I just realized?
방금 깨달은 건데 말야
We have no idea what we're doing in the wedding tomorrow.
우리 둘다 내일 결혼식 때
뭘 해야 할 지 모르고 있어
Yeah, I thought we'd be groomsmen, but wouldn't they have asked us by now?
그러게, 신랑 들러리면
지금 쯤은 말해줬어야 되지 않나?
신부 들러리는 언제 부탁 받았어?
When did they ask you to be a bridesmaid?
Uh, November.
I want to say it's not looking good
11월?
이거 별로 느낌이 안좋은데...
- 피비?
- 왜?
Hey, Phoebes?
Sorry?
아직 얘네들한테 뭘 할 지
말 안해줬어?
You haven't told these guys what they are doing in the wedding yet.
아무 것도 안맡았으니까
Um, well, they're not in the wedding. What?
뭐라구?
Well... this is really awkward.
내 입장이 난처하네...
나는 빠져도 되는구나
Oh, and I can leave.
I'm sorry, you guys.But, you know, Mike's got his brother and his friends from school,
미안해, 얘들아
그런데...
마이크는 형도 있고
동창들도 있어서...
so, you know, you were... if it helps, you were next in line. You just missed the cut.
위로가 될 지 모르겠지만
정말 아깝게 안된 거야
Oh, man.
This is like figure skating team all over again.
이럴 수가
피겨스케이트 팀에서의
아픈 기억이 떠오르는구만!
아니, 수중 발레!
I mean, synchronized swimming. I mean... I mean, the balance beam.
아니 아니, 평균대 운동!
- 살려줘!
- 풋볼!
Help me.
Football.
Thank you.
고마워
피비, 그거 뱉어
그 안에 돼지고기 들어있어
Oh, Phoebes. Spit that out. That has pork in it.
Oh!
야채 군만두 아냐?
I thought the pot stickers were supposed to be vegetarian.
Yeah. I changed them. I sent you a fax about it.
내가 바꿨어
바꿨다고 팩스 보냈는데?
난 팩스 없는데?
I don't have a fax machine.
그래? 그럼 놀랄 일이
몇개 더 있겠네
Huh. Well, then there are going to be a few surprises.
우리만 맡은 일이 없다니
믿을 수가 없어
I can't believe we're going to be the only people that aren't in this wedding.
I know. I hate being left out of things. And it's a wedding. It'll be weird if I'm not in it.
이런데 못끼는 거 정말 싫어하는데
결혼식이잖아!
내가 안낀다는 건 말이 안돼
안녕? 좋은 시간 보내고 있어?
Hey, guys. How's it going?
좋지
Fine. We're just sitting here, alone, doing nothing.
여기 외롭게 앉아있지...
아무 것도 안하고...
It's our rehearsal for tomorrow.
내일을 위한 리허설 중이라고
Yeah, look, about tomorrow, I've got a question for you.
그래서 말인데, 물어볼 게 있어
I just found out that one of my groomsman had an emergency and can't make it.
신랑 들러리 중 한명이
급한 일 때문에 올 수가 없대
What happened?
Who cares? And?
- 무슨 일이래?
- 무슨 상관이야, 그래서?
And I was wondering if, you know, maybe one of you guys.../I'll do it./Me, me!
그래서 너희 둘 중에 한 명이...
- 내가 할게!
- 나! 나!
둘 다 하고 싶은 거야?
You both want to do it? There's only room for one.
한 사람만 필요한데
날 골라라, 나 턱시도 아주 잘
어울리는데, 눈에 띄진 않아
Pick me. I look great in a tux and I will not steal focus.
아냐, 내가 할게, 왜냐면...
No. Mike, no, no. You want to pick me. I mean... watch.
잘 봐!
죽이지?
Ah?!
내가 정하긴 좀 힘들 것 같다
You know, I really don't feel very comfortable making this decision.
You know, Phoebe knows you better.I'm going to let her choose.
피비가 너희들을 더 잘 아니깐
피비 보고 정하라고 할게
Well... if Phoebe is choosing, then say hello to Mike's next groomsman.
피비가 정한다니깐 말인데...
마이크의 들러리 될 이 몸에게
인사나 하시지?
그래주지!
그런데 거울이 필요한 걸?
Oh, I will. But I will need a mirror... as he is me.
왜냐면 그건 나니까!
왜 이러셔... 넌 안돼
Please. You're going down./You are going downer.
너야말로 더 안돼!
피켜스케이팅 팀에서 그러든?
Is that what they say on the figure skating team?
나도 몰라, 안끼워줬다니까!
I wouldn't know, I didn't make it.
내가 피비의 아버지 대신해서
들어가는 거 알지?
So, you know I'm filling in for Phoebe's stepdad tomorrow, right?
응, 부탁 들어줘서 고마워
Yeah, yeah. Thanks for doing that./Oh, hey, my pleasure.
천만에
그래서 우리 피비랑 어쩌겠다는건가?
So what are your intentions with my Phoebe?
결혼하려고 하는데
I intend to marry her.
Oh... a wise acre.
말은 잘하는 구만
피아노나 쳐가지고
마누라 먹여살리려 하는건가?
So, I understand you plan to support your wife by playing the piano?
좀 불안정하지 않나?
Isn't that kind of unstable?
배우보단 안정적일 것 같은데
No more so than acting./Strike two.
스트라이크 2!
네 말이 맞아
피비가 날 먹여살리겠지
You're right. She probably will support me.Hey, unless we move in with you, dad.
아빠랑 같이 살면 되겠네요
스트라이크 3!
Strike three.
You only get one more, Mike.
하나만 더 하면 아웃일세, 마이크
So, What, uh, what did you decide?
어떻게 하기로 했어?
화장실 가기로 했는데?
I decided to pee.
마이크가 얘기 안했어?
Mike didn't tell you? You have to choose one of us to be in your wedding.
신랑 들러리가 한명 빠져서
우리 둘 중 한명을 네가 골라야 해
One of his groomsmen fell out.
안돼, 내가 너희 둘 중에서
고를 수는 없어
Oh, no, no. I can't choose between you two.I love you both so much.
난 너희 둘 다 똑같이 사랑한단 말야
신랑 들러리로는
좀 부족하긴 하지만 말이지?
Just not enough to put us in the original wedding party.
정말 못하겠어
Oh... but I don't want to choose. It'S...
너무... 아! 레이첼!
oh, okay, wait. Rach! /Yeah?
Um, listen, I have a very special bridesmaid task for you to do.
너를 위한 아주 특별한
신부 들러리용 임무가 있어
와~ 신난다, 뭔데 뭔데?
Oh! Goodie! What is it?
신랑 들러리가 한자리 남았는데
Well, there's a spot open for only one groomsman
로스랑 챈들러 중
한명을 고르는 거야
and you have to choose between Ross and Chandler.
So, good luck with that.
잘 해봐
뭐...뭐라구!
싫어 싫어 나 안해!
What? What? No, no. I don't-- don't want to do that.
All right. I guess I have to find a new bridesmaid. /I'll do it!
알았어, 신부 들러리 한명도
새로 찾아야겠네
내가 할게!
자, 21시00분이다
건배 10초전!
Okay, it's 21:00 hours. Time for your toasts.
Do I have a minute to go to the bathroom?
화장실 갈 시간도 없어?
You had a bathroom break at 20:30. Pee on your own time, Mike!
휴식 시간은 20시30분이었다!
휴식 시간에 화장실도 안갔나?
마이크?!
Now... in regards to the toast, okay, you want to keep them short.
건배시 연설이 길면 분위기 망친다
알겠나?
오랫동안 길게 얘기하지 말도록
Nothing kills a rehearsal dinner like long speeches.
Okay, you just get in, do your thing and get out.
들어가서 할 일하고 바로 빠진다
너 챈들러한테도 그렇게 말하니?
Is that what you say to chandler?
It's 21:01 and I am not amused.
현재시간 21시01분
그걸 개그라고 하나?!
자, 신랑신부가 간단하게
인사를 드리겠습니다
Okay, the bride and groom have a few words they'd like to say.
Okay. Hello, everyone. And thank you all for being here tonight.
안녕하세요, 여러분
오늘 참석해주셔서 감사합니다
드디어 내일이 식이에요
So tomorrow's the big event.
모르시는 분들도 있겠지만
And some of you might not know, but Mike and I didn't get off to the best start.
마이크랑 제가 시작부터
순조롭진 않아서
Um, yeah, my, um...
조이랑 저는 서로 친구를
소개시켜주기로 했죠
My friend Joey and I, decided to fix each other up with friends, so...
그래서 제가...
I-I... oh, okay. I, um...
알았어...
제가... 곰곰히 생각해 보고
I-I gave it a lot of thought and I fixed him up with my friend Mary Ellen,
오늘은 참석하지 못한 제 친구
메리엘렌을 소개시켜주려고 했는데
who couldn't be here tonight because...
it's not... not important. Well, she's in rehab.
이건 별로 중요하지 않겠네요
그 애는 재활훈련 중이거든요
어쨌든, 조이가 자기 친구
마이클을 소개시켜 준다고 했는데
Anyway, so okay, yeah.
So, Joey said that he was fixing me up with his friend Mike,
마이클이라는 친구가 없는 관계로...
only he didn't have a friend Mike, so he just brought, uh, my Mike. And, and...
여기... 제 신랑인...
마이크를 데려온 거죠...
뭐... 암튼 잘됐다구요
but despite, you know, it got, it got good.
Okay, I want to take a moment to mention my mother who couldn't be here.
그리고 여기 오실 수 없는 저희
어머니에 대해 잠깐 말씀드리고 싶네요
세상에...
Oh, god.
다 했어요!
And... and moment's over.
So, okay. Um... oh, no. Forget that. I can forget that, and, oh, this is funny...
이건 됐구요
여기 재미있는게 있는데
아까 그걸 들어야 아는 거고...
but you need to know that to... to get that, so...
그래서... 이건...
oh, well, okay, um...
I... okay... there... okay, Monica, I can't do it like this!
이건...
모니카! 이렇게는 못하겠어!
이건 내 결혼이라구!
This is my wedding, okay? I don't want, I don't want this.
알겠어?! 이런 것도 싫고...
Or this. Or this. Okay?
이렇게 하기도 싫고...
이것도 싫고...
알겠어?! 난 그저 평범한
결혼식을 바라는 것 뿐이라구
I just wanted a simple wedding where my fiancee can go to the bathroom anytime he wants!
내 약혼자가 화장실에
가고 싶을 때 갈 수 있게 말야!
너 이제 그만 해라
You know what, you're done. /What? /You're fired!
- 뭐?
- 넌 짤렸어!
건배하죠
Cheers.
Hey. Happy wedding day!
결혼 축하해!!
Oh, happy my wedding day to you.
나도 내 결혼 축하해!
Okay, now, Joey, listen. This is going to be bridesmaid central, all right?
좋아, 조이
이제 신부 들러리들도 준비해야 해
화장실에선 머리랑 화장을 할거고
We're going to have hair and makeup going on in the bathroom
and, uh, oh, I had to move a couple things in the fridge to make room for the corsages.
냉동실에 코사지를 넣어야되서
물건들을 좀 치웠어
Oh, man. I wouldn't have had breakfast if I knew there was going to be corsages.
세상에, 코사지를 넣을걸 알았다면
아침 안먹었을거 아냐
* 코사지 - 결혼식 때 가슴에 다는 꽃
안녕
Hi. Um... about last night.
어젯밤에 말야...
너무 스트레스 받은거 이해해
I know you're under a lot of stress, and, uh, well,
네가 비록 나한테...
상처를 주긴 했지만 말야
even though the things you said hurt me a little bit...
uh, my point is, uh, well, I'm willing to take my job back.
내 말은...
내가 다시 할게
Oh, well, that's okay.
아냐, 괜찮아
I think, I think you and I will do much better if you're just, you know, here as a bridesmaid.
너 그냥 신부 들러리만 해줘
Oh. Is that so? Okay.
그래?
뭐 네가 원한다면...
If that's really what you want, then, here. I give you the headset.
여기, 헤드셋 줄게
아냐, 주기 싫어
Well, I don't really want to give you the headset.
이제 네가 할 거면
이 메세지들도 확인해줘야겠다
Yeah, well, I guess if you're taking over, then you should probably return these messages.
이런 정말 많네
Oh, this is a lot.
/Uh-huh. But I-I'm sure you can handle this.
쫌 많지
그래도 잘 할 수 있을거야
물론 나야 스케줄 관리 분야에서
상도 탔지만서도
I mean, I have won awards for my organizational skills, but I'm sure you'll do fine.
- 너도 분명히 잘 할 수 있을거야
- 상을 탔다고?
You've won awards?
/Mm-hmm. I printed them out on my computer.
그럼, 내가 컴퓨터로 뽑아놨어
- 안녕
- 어서 와
Hey.
/Hi.
/Where's Rach?
- 레이첼 어디 있어?
- 방에, 왜?
She's in her room. Why?
신랑 들러리 결정하는 것
때문에 얘기 좀 해야하거든
Oh, I have to talk to her about this groomsman situation, okay?
챈들러가 앞에 서 있는 걸
가만히 보고만 있진 않을거야
I'm not gonna watch Chandler up there while I'm sitting in the seats like some chump.
자리에 멍청하게
앉아있으면서 말야!
세상에! 너 오늘 너무 예쁘다~
My god, you're breathtaking.
/What do you want?
뭐 때문에 그래?
신랑 들러리 아직 안골랐지?
You haven't, by any chance, chosen a groomsman yet, have you?
로스, 제발
네가 안그래도 너무 힘들어
Oh, Ross, come on, please. Don't make this harder than it already is.
아니야, 더 쉽게 해주려는거야
나로 해~!
I'm not. I'm making it easier. Pick me.
Well, Chandler said that it's really important to him, too.
/Listen, listen.
챈들러가 자기한테도
아주 중요하댔어
잘 들어 봐
Whoever you pick is going to walk down the aisle with you.
넌 네가 뽑은 사람이랑
같이 입장하잖아
난 아무 말 안하고 조용히
걷기만 할게, 약속해
Now, I promise, I won't say a word, but if you pick Chandler,
하지만 챈들러랑 입장하면
he's going to be whispering stupid jokes in your ear the whole time.
계속 네 귀에다 되고
말도 안되는 농담이나 할 거라구!
그래, 그나마 네가 낫겠다
Oh, you are the lesser of two evils.
/Yes!
그렇지!!
스벤씨, 무슨 소릴하는 거에요!
Sven, I don't understand what you're saying.
꽃이 어쨌다는 거에요?
What is wrong with the flowers? Lorkins? What the hell are lorkins?
로킨스? 그게 뭔데요!
난 알지롱~
I know.
안녕~
Hey.
마이크, 만약 스웨덴 사람이
"로킨스"라고 말한다면
Listen, Mike, if you were swedish and you were saying the word "lorkins,"
무슨 꽃일것 같아?
what flower would that be?
난초?
Orchids?
/Right there. That's why I'm marrying you.
바로 그거야!
그래서 내가 너랑 결혼하는거야
마이클군 왔나?
Hello, Michael.
/Joseph.
조셉...
잠깐 얘기 좀 나눌 수 있을까?
May I have a word with you, please?
방이... 좋네
This is... is great.
/Have a seat.
앉게
어젯밤에...
Last night... I tried to welcome you into my family.
난 자넬 가족으로서
환영해주려고 했네
그런데 자넨 날 무시했네
Instead you disrespect me. I cannot allow this.
그런 건 용납할 수 없어
무슨 마피아 영화 연습하는거야?
Are you rehearsing for some really bad mafia movie?
또 말대답
More backtalk.
맞긴 맞아
And yes, I may be borrowing a few lines from my recent
최근에 떨어진 "Family honor 2
This time, it's a personal" 오디션에서
unsuccessful audition for family honor 2: This-a time, it's-a personal.
몇 줄 따오긴 했지
조이, 나 오늘 할 일이
아주 많거든, 할 말이 뭔데?
Joey, I kind of have a lot to do today. What do you, what do you want?
이걸 진지하게 받아들이라구!
I want you to take this seriously.
피비는 나한테 아주 아주 중요한 사람이야, 알겠어?
Phoebe is very, very important to me, okay?
그리고 넌 그런 사람을
데려가는거라는 거라구
And I want to make sure that you are going to take care of her.
Well... Joe, I love Phoebe.
있잖아, 조이
난 피비를 사랑해
내 인생에서 가장
중요한 사람이라구
She's the single most important thing in my life.
내 목숨을 걸고
행복하게 해줄거야
I'd die before I'd let anything happen to her.
바로 그런 걸 듣고 싶었다니깐
That's what I wanted to hear, because she's family, okay?
피비는 내 가족이니까, 알았어?
이젠 너도 가족이 되는거고
And now you're gonna be family,
그리고 세상에 가족보다
더 소중한 건 없어
and there's nothing more important in the whole world than family.
그거 아주 구린 영화였겠다
That must have been one lousy movie.
내가 한 말이야!
That was me!
안녕
Hi.
Hey. Can I talk to you about this groomsman thing?
신랑 들러리 얘기 좀 할까?
If you pick Ross, you know, he'll walk you down the aisle just fine,
로스를 고른다면
입장이야 잘 하겠지
하지만 나를 고른다면...
but if you choose me, you'll be getting some comedy.
아주 재미있을거야!
그렇긴 하지만...
Even so...
I think I'm going to pick Ross.
로스를 선택해야할 것 같아
왜 나를 뽑아야 하는지 들어봐
Let me tell you why you need to pick me.
Okay.
어렸을 때 난 항상
따돌림을 당했어
see, when I was a kid, you know, I was always left out of everything,
그래서 좌절도 많이 했지
you know, and it really made me feel... insecure, you know.
항상... 체육시간에도
꼴찌로 뽑혔었어
I was always picked last in gym,
심지어 야구를 어떻게 하는지도
모르는 뚱뚱한 교환학생보다도 나중에
even behind that big, fat exchange student who didn't even know the rules to baseball.
I mean, this guy would strike out and then run to third.
걘 삼진아웃을 당하곤
3루로 뛰었을 정도였지
어쨌든, 나만 이 결혼식에서 빠지면
Anyway, if I'm the only one left out of this wedding,
그 아픈 기억들이 다시
다 생각날 것 같아
I just know that all those feelings are going to come rushing back.
알았어, 좋아. 널 뽑을게
All right, fine, I pick you.
/Y-y-yes!
그렇지!!
이 들러리 챈들러를 위해
결혼식 자리를 비워두시라~
Make groom for Chandler.
세상에...
Oh, my.
안돼요, 내가 말한대로 해요
No, we're gonna do it my way.
Because your way is stupid.
그건 말이 안되니깐요
All right, I gotta go. I have another call, Reverend.
그만 끊어요
전화가 와서요, 목사님
여보세요
Hello.
이렇게 얘기하고 나니 참 기쁘다
I'm glad we had this little talk.
응, 그래
Yes. Yeah, and thanks for all the wedding night advice.
첫날밤에 대한 충고 고마워
전혀 어색하지도 않았구...
That didn't make me uncomfortable at all.
그럼 이따 저녁 때 보자
All right, and so I-I'll see everybody tonight.
- 응
- 잘 가
Okay.
/Bye.
너희들 복도에
얼음 조각 있는 것 봤어?
Uh, did you guys know that there's a giant ice sculpture in the hall?
세상에~ 이게 왜 여기 있어?
Oh, my god, what's it doing here?
배달 주소로 안보내고
돈 내는 주소로 보냈나봐
I guess it got sent to the billing address as opposed to the shipping address.
Oh! What a pickle.
난리 났네
세상에, 모든 게 엉망이야
My god. Everything's such a mess.Why is this happening to me?!
내가 뭘 잘못했냐구!
저기에 혀가 붙으면 재미있겠다
How bad do you want to stick your tongue on that?
별 일 없어?
How's it going?
/Good.
좋아
I'm just getting some coffee so I'm alert for the wedding.
커피 마시고
결혼식에 참여할 준비하려고
That's what I was doing, too.
나도 그러려고 했는데
그래, 즐거운 밤 보내라
Well, uh... you have fun tonight.
/You, too.
/Oh, I will.
너도
아마 그럴거야
나도
Me, too.
잠깐... 내가 재수없게 구는 건
맞지만, 넌 왜그래?
Wait a minute. I know why I'm being such an ass. Why are you?
말할 수 없을 것 같은데
I'm not supposed to tell you.
나야말로 말하면 안되는데...
I'm not supposed to tell YOU.
우리 둘 다한테 맡기겠다고 한거야?!
You told us both we could be in the wedding?
Well... in my defense... you weren't supposed to tell each other.
너희들 서로 말 안하기로 했잖아!
레이첼, 한명만 된다고 했잖아
한명만 뽑으라고!
Rachel, only one of us can do it. You have to choose.
You and me together again.
너랑 나랑 한번 더 하자
레이첼 레이첼, 똑똑
Rach, Rach, knock-knock.
/Who's there?
누구세요?
I'll tell you at the wedding.
결혼식 때 말해줄게요
안녕, 목도리를 두고 가서
Hey, I forgot my scarf.
그거 알아? 난 못하겠어
You know what? I can't do this. I don't know which one of you guys to pick.
누굴 골라야 할지 모르겠다구
아직 안골랐어?
Oh, you haven't picked yet?
Oh, good, 'cause I had, I had an idea.
잘됐다, 내가 생각해 낸 게 있거든
우리집 강아지 '채피'를
들러리로 하면 재미있을 것 같아
I thought it would be fun if a third groomsman was my family dog, Chappy.
뭐라구? 멍멍이?
What? A dog? No. Rachel gets to choose.
안돼, 레이첼, 빨리 골라
이거 너무 어렵다
Wow, this is a tough one.
강아지가 하면 좋을 것 같아
I think I'm gonna have to go with the dog.
All right, wait, wait. So, what, what you're saying is that-that the chef is at the hamilton club, but the food is not,
잠깐만요, 그러니까
요리사는 해밀턴 클럽에 왔는데
음식은 안왔고...
and the drinks are there, but the bartender is not? Are-are-are you freaking kidding me?!
음료수는 왔는데
바텐더는 안왔다는 거에요?
지금 농담하는 거에요?!
어떻게 돼가?
How's it going?
나 좀 도와줘
Help me.
/What?
뭐라고?
다시 한번 미친 짓 해달라구
I want you to be crazy bitch again.
Really?
/Please.
진짜?
제발~
You really want me to come back?
진짜로 내가 해줬으면 하는거야?
결혼하고 싶은만큼 보다 더
More than I want to get married.
좋아, 여러분
다시 시작합니다!!
Okay, people, we are back in business!
세상에, 네가 너무 그리웠어!
Oh, god, I have missed you so much.
좋아, 가서 머리하고 화장해
Okay. Go get your hair and makeup done and I'll take care of everything.
나머지는 내가 다 알아서 할게
얘들아, 어떡할거야?
Hey, what are you guys gonna do?
뭘?
About what?
눈보라가 쳐!
The blizzard. I just saw on the news.
뉴스에서 20년만에 최악의 눈사태래
It's like the worst snowstorm in 20 years. They already closed all the bridges and tunnels.
이미 다리랑 터널 모두 폐쇄됐대
뭐라구? 밴드랑 사진사가
뉴저지에서 오기로 되어있는데
What? But... but the band and the photographer are coming all the way in from new Jersey.
못올 것 같은데
I don't think they are.
Ha-ha. Looks like you're not going to be in the wedding either.
너도 결혼식에 못끼겠구나
너무 안됐다, 피비
So sorry, Pheebs.
Well, the club lost its power.
결혼식장에 전기가 나갔대
도시 전체가 그렇다고 뉴스에 나왔어
Yeah, according to the news, most of the city did.
네가 언제 뉴스를 봤다고 그래?
Since when do you watch the news?
Uh, for your information, since they hired a very hot weather girl.
정 알고 싶다면... 끝내주는
기상 리포터가 나오면서부터야
너희가 오늘 결혼하지 못한다는게
안믿겨져
I can't believe you guys aren't going to be able to get married today.
내 말이 그 말이야
I know.
/Well, you know, it's so beautiful out there.
그런데 밖에 정말 아름답다
너희들 항상 야외에서
결혼하고 싶어했잖아
You always wanted to get married outside.Why don't you guys just do it on the street?
그냥 눈쌓인 길에서 하면 어때?
뭐라구?
What?
/Well, look, it's hardly snowing anymore.
봐... 이제 눈도 거의 안오잖아
더이상 로맨틱할 순 없을 것 같은데?
I mean, you couldn't ask for a more romantic setting.
그리고 네가 항상 원했던 것처럼
검소한 결혼식이고
This could be the simple wedding you've always wanted.
어때?
What do you think?
난 자기랑 오늘 결혼하고 싶어
I think I want to get married to you today.
나도
Me, too. Monica, do you think we could do it?
모니카, 될 것 같아?
네, 그렇습니다!
Affirmative.
자, 의자는 바깥에 내놓구요
Okay, let's get these chairs out here.
Gunther, hit the christmas lights.
건터, 크리스마스 조명을 점등한다
실시!
Ah...
okay, who left the ice sculpture on the steam grate?!
누가 얼음조각을 김 나는
맨홀 위에 놓으랬나!
마이클
Michael.
아, 오셨군요, 다행이에요
Hey, you made it. Great. Chappy!
채피~!
There you go.
Hi. Hi.
어머니, 길에서 결혼하는거
좋아하시지 않을 줄은 알지만
Mom, I know getting married in the street isn't something you approve of...
아니다, 너무 멋져
조명이랑 눈이...
No, it's lovely. The lights and the snow... I could look at them forever.
아무리 봐도 멋진 걸
내가 네 엄마 잔에 약을 좀 탔다
I crushed a pill and put it in her drink.
이리 와요, 여보
Come on, sweetheart.
알다시피 채피가 혼자
눈 위를 걷기에 너무 작으니까
You know, Chappy's too small to handle all this snow.
누가 잡고 입장을 해야할 것 같은데
Someone's going to have to walk him down the aisle.
그 사람도 결혼식에 끼는 거네?
So, technically, would this person be in the wedding?
I guess.
/I'll do it.
그렇겠지?
- 내가 할게!
잠깐, 안돼, 챈들러, 야!
Wait, no, but, Chandler, hello?
내 말은.., 너 개 무섭지 않아?
I mean, aren't you, aren't you scared of dogs?
아니~
I'm not scared.
요 귀여운 채피를 안고...
I'll just take little Chappy and... he can sense my fear! My throat is exposed!
얘가 내 목을 물려고 한 것 같아!
아무래도 내가 해야겠군
Well, I guess I'm in the wedding, then. Ha, ha! He stinks.
냄새!
적색 경보! 반복한다!
Level one alert! I repeat, level one! This is not a drill. Okay, we've got a situation.
1급 경보! 실제 상황이다!
문제가 생겼어
The minister just called. He's snowed in, he can't make it.
목사님이 전화를 했는데
눈 때문에 못오시겠대
Oh, no.
/Oh, hey, don't worry.
안돼~
걱정 마, 너 결혼식 때
목사님께 안수받은거 아직 유효해
I'm still ordained from your wedding.
- 정말?
- 그래~
Really?
/Yeah.
내가 지하철비 면제해주는
목사를 그만뒀을 것 같아?
You think I'd give up being a minister and start paying to ride the subway?
그런데 목사도 지하철은 돈내고 타
Uh, ministers don't ride the subway for free.
성경을 좀 자세히 읽어야하긴 했지만...
맞아, 공짜야
I had to read the bible pretty carefully, but, yeah, we do.
좋아, 조이가 식을 진행하면
누가 피비를 데리고 입장하지?
Okay, if Joey does the ceremony, then we have to find someone else to walk Phoebe down the aisle.
내가 할게!
I'll do it!
/ha, ha!
께겡~
좋아, 마이크랑 조이, 위치로
Okay, Mike and Joey, get in position.
Chandler, come with me.
챈들러는 날 따라와
좋아, 조이가 식을 올리게 되서
챈들러가 널 데리고 갈거야
Okay, Joey's doing the ceremony, and Chandler's giving you away.
Oh, okay. Hi, new dad.
알았어
안녕, 새 아빠
So, you ready to do this?
준비됐어?
세상에 나 정말 결혼하는거지?
Uh-huh, uh-huh. Oh, my god. This is really happening.
Mm-hmm. Oh, Phoebe, I'm so happy for you, honey.
응
피비, 정말 축하해
Oh, thank you.
고마워
I love you.
/Oh...
사랑해
잠깐 잠깐...
껴안지 마, 드레스 구겨져
wait, wait, wait, wait, no, no hugs. The dresses.
- 무슨 상관이야
- 이리와~
Oh, what the hell.
/Oh, come on.
- 사랑해 얘들아
- 사랑해
I love you guys.
/Love you.
Okay, it's zero hour.
좋아, 작전시간이다!
All teams execute on my count.
모든 팀은 내 지시에 따라 움직인다
Let's get this bad boy on the road.
자 시작하자구!
자기야, 이따 밤에
그 헤드셋 쓰고 오면 안될까?
Is it okay that I want you to wear that headset in bed tonight?
23시00분에 자기 누드가 예정돼있어
Uh, I have you scheduled for nudity at 23:00 hours.
오, 예~
Oh, yeah.
자, 마조리, 연주 개시!
Okay, Marjorie, hit it.
세상에 로스, 샤워는 했어야지
Geez, Ross, you could have showered.
/It's the dog.
개 냄새라니까!
들러리씨, 왜 거기 서있어요?
Groomsmen, why are you just standing there? Where is your bridesmaid?
들러리 파트너는 어디 있죠?
긴급 상황 발생!
We've got a broken arrow. Bridesmaid down.
신부 들러리가 당했다!
나구나
Oh, it's me.
준비됐어?
Ready?
/Okay.
- 응
- 좋아
잠깐, 안되지, 잠깐..
Wait. Oh, no. Wait.
Wow.
안춥겠어?
But aren't you going to be cold?
/I don't care.
상관 없어
내가 결혼식에 필요한 파란색이 되지 뭐
* 미국 결혼식에는
파란색 물품을 사용하는 것이 관례
I'll-I'll-I'll be my "something blue."
- 정말 예쁘다
- 고마워
You look beautiful.
/Thank you.
Oh, my god. Aren't you freezing?
/Nah-ah.
- 세상에, 안추워?
- 하나도
형제, 가족...
Friends, family, dog,
강아지 여러분...
이 축복받은 예식에
함께 해주셔서 감사합니다
thank you all for you being here to witness this blessed event.
이제 추위가 내 특별한 곳까지
퍼져 오네요
The cold has now spread to my special place.
고로 짧게 말씀드리죠
So I'm gonna do the short version of this.
피비와 마이크는
서로에게 완벽한 한쌍입니다
Phoebe and Mike are perfect for each other. And I know I speak for everyone here
그리고 둘의 영원한 행복을
빌어주는 바입니다
when I wish in my lifetime of happiness.
반지는 어디있죠?
Who has the rings?
Okay.
내가 어렸을 때 나에게는
부모님이 없었어요
When I was growing up, I didn't have normal mom and dad,
다른 사람같은 평범한 가족도 없었구요
or regular family like everybody else.
뭔가 없다는 걸 항상 느꼈었죠
and I always knew that someing was missing
하지만 오늘 여기에...
Now I'm standing here today
앞으로 가질 수 있는 모든 걸
다 가진 채 서있습니다
knowing that I have everything I'm ever going to need. You are my family.
당신은 제 가족이에요
피비, 당신은 너무 아름답습니다
Phoebe you are so beautiful.
너무나 친절하고 관대하며
You are so kind, you are so generous.
You are so wonderfuly weird.
놀라울만큼 특이하죠
당신과의 하루하루는 모험입니다
Everyday with you is an adventure.
내가 얼마나 운이 좋은지
믿기지가 않습니다
I can't believe how lucky I am.
당신과 평생을 함께하고 싶습니다
I can't wait to share my life with you forever.
잠깐요, 까먹은 게 있어요
Oh, wait I forgot. "and I love you" "and you have nice eyes".
당신을 사랑합니다
당신은 눈이 아름답구요
나도 사랑합니다
I love you, too.
저기, 조이...
Uh, Joey, Chappy's heart rate has slowed way down.
채피의 심장이 점점 천천히 뛰고 있어
좋아요, 피비...
Okay, Phoebe, do you take this man to be your husband?
/I do.
이 사람을 당신의
남편으로 맞이하겠습니까?
네
Mike, do you take this woman to be your wife?
/I do.
마이크...
이 사람을 당신의
아내로 맞이하겠습니까?
네
이 두사람이 부부가 되었음을
선언합니다
I now pronounce you "husband and wife".
나 결혼했다~!
I got married.
Could someone get me a coat? I'm freaking freezing.
누구 코트 좀 가져다줄래?
추워 죽을 것 같아
너무 멋진 결혼식이었어
It really was a incredible wedding.
It was. I kind of don't want it to end.
응, 끝나는게 아까웠다니까
Hey you want to come in for a drink by the corsage?
들어와서 코사지랑
맥주 한잔 안할래?
그러고 싶지만 23시00분에
지상최대로 계획된 섹스를 하기로 했거든
I'd love to, but it's 23:00 hours and I have the most organized sex anyone's ever had.
잘됐다
근데 로스는 어디간거야?
Nice. Hey whatever happend to Ross?
모르겠는데, 아마 아까 얘기하던
그 예쁜 여자랑 같이 있겠지 뭐...
I don't know. Maybe he hooked up with the hot girl he was talking to.
제발 채피, 할 일은 해야지
Come on, Chappy. Do your business. Make! Make!
싸!
싸라구!
이거까지 하기로 하진 않았었는데
I did not sign on for this.